Joanne Alter Paper
University of Illinois at Chicago
Joanne Alter Paper
1939-1952
University of Illinois at Chicago
Alter, Joanne
47 linear ft.
Joanne Hammerman Alter is a Chicago-based politician, activist and organizer who served as Commissioner of the Metropolitan Sanitary District of Greater Chicago for 18 years. Her papers reflect her involvement in politics and cultural organizations, and contain primarily literature, photos, correspondence, speeches, meeting minutes, clippings, and campaign memorabilia.
JAlter
Biographical Sketch
Joanne Hammerman Alter is a Chicago-based politician, activist, and organizer. Her interests and activities span a wide variety of issues including environmental, education, feminist, and cultural issues and affairs. She served as the Commissioner of the Metropolitan Sanitary District of Greater Chicago from 1972 through 1990, and worked with numerous social services and cultural advisory boards after this period. She is the recipient of numerous awards commemorating her work for women, the environment, and her leadership in the arts.
Born July 3, 1927, Joanne Hammerman was the daughter of Sol and Celia Hammerman in one of the few Jewish families on the North Shore in the 1930's. She attended Mount Holyoke College, graduating Cum Laude in 1949. She married James M. Alter in 1952 and raised four children.
She got involved in politics in the 1950s when she served as secretary to the Young Democrats. She worked on several campaigns before deciding to run for office. In 1972, she became the first woman to win a countywide office on a democratic ticket with the seat of Commissioner of the Metropolitan Sanitary District (MSD). Founded in 1889 as the Sanitation District of Chicago, the name was changed in 1955 to reflect the regional scope of work that MSD undertook. In 1972, MSD started the Tunnel and Reservoir Plan (TARP), a long-term project to address the combined sewer overflow problem. Alter brought an environmental activist's perspective to her office, and also led the agency to take a leadership role in the cleanup and redevelopment of the Chicago River. In 1989 MSD changed their name to the Metropolitan Water Reclamation District of Greater Chicago in celebration of their centennial anniversary.
Alter also ran unsuccessfully for two outside offices during her time at MSD. In 1976 she distinguished herself as the first woman to run for statewide office as Lieutenant Governor. In 1990 she ran for County Clerk on a platform of electoral reform. Her political work extended well into the Democratic Party, as she co-founded the Illinois Democratic Womens Organization and served several times as delegate to the Democratic National Convention.
Alter engaged her passion for social issues through a variety of volunteer outlets. She founded and worked with the Junior Museum of the Art Institute of Chicago for several years. Upon completing her term as MSD commissioner in 1990, Alter mobilized volunteer public school tutors and co-founded Working in The Schools (WITS), Alter remained a resident of Chicago's North Side throughout her life.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials collected by Alter throughout much of her professional life, and covers political campaigns, her work as commissioner, and other volunteer and leadership activities. Materials primarily include literature, correspondence, clippings, photos, slides, speeches, memos, minutes, campaign memorabilia and ephemera, scrapbook and audiotapes.
The materials cover several accessions dating from 1980-1991. The Series organizations represents the order and integrity of accessions, and is divided into the following: Campaigns, Personal Papers, Metropolitan Sanitary District, Democratic Party and Affiliates, Organizational Work, Tunnel and Reservoir Plan, and Oversized Items. The sub series do contain reorganized files ordered by chronology or subject.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Alter, Joanne H. (Joanne Hammerman), 1927- --Archives.; Women political activists--Illinois--Biography--Sources.
Midwest Women's History; Chicago Political and Civic Life
Detailed Description/Box and Folder Listing
- Series I: Campaigns
  - Scope and Content note: This series contains literature, correspondence, clippings and other documentation related to Alter's campaigns for Commissioner of the Metropolitan Sanitation District and Lieutenant Governor of Illinois. The sub-series are divided by campaign and are ordered chronologically.
  - Sub-Series A: 1972 Campaign for Metropolitan Sanitation District Commissioner
    - Coffee Thank-Yous, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Contributor Thank-Yous, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Contributor Thank-Yous, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Endorsements, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Press Releases, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Independent Voters of Illinois, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Campaign Strategy, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - Primary Election, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Events, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - Congratulations, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Schedule, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Calendar, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence - Contributors Letters, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Mailing Lists, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Clippings - Other Candidates, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Election Laws and Procedures, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Inauguration, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Other Candidates, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Endorsements, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Strategy, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Staff, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Bills, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Organizational Lists and Directories, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Other Candidates - Clippings, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Election, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Press Releases [photo], 1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Events, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Sub-Series B: 1974 Campaigns of Other Candidates
    - Miscellaneous [clippings], 1974 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Sub-Series C: 1976 Campaign for Lieutenant Governor
    - Coffee Kits, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Friend to Friend program, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Attorney General Candidates - Ron Stackler, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - State of Illinois - Executive Orders, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - State of Illinois - Budget Releases, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Advertising, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Telegrams, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Candidates - Joan Anderson for Lt. Governor, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Candidates - Michael Howlett for Governor, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Petitions, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Schedule, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Requests for Inspection of Finance Records, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Candidate Questionnaires, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Women Candidates and Organizations, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Biography of Alter, c. 1976 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Clippings, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Clippings, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Clippings - Other Candidates, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Clippings - Criminal Justice, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Clippings -Other Candidates, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Clippings - Secretary of State Michael Howlett, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Clippings - Metropolitan Sanitation District, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Clippings - Governor Walker,, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Speaking Events, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Thank Yous, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Thank Yous, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Thank Yous, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Thank Yous, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Thank Yous, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Media, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Media, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Speeches, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Press Releases, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Schedule, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Clippings from Other Campaigns, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Clippings, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Campaign Manuals, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 84)
    - Clippings, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 85)
    - Petition for Nomination, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 86)
    - Clippings, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 87)
    - Speeches and Presentations, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 88)
    - Speeches and Presentations, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 89)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 90)
    - Miscellaneous [photos], 1976 (Box 10, Folder 91)
    - Walker/Alter Radio Debate [reel tapes], 1976 (Box 10, Folder 92)
    - Schedule, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 93)
    - Mailing and Organization List, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    - Fundraising, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 95)
    - Press Releases, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 97)
    - Press Releases, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 98)
    - Biography and Briefing Statements, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Sub-Series D: 1978 Campaign for Metropolitan Sanitation District Commissioner
    - Alter Re-election, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Miscellaneous [photos], 1998 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Media, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Requests for Inspection of Reports, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - Clippings, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - Media, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - Legal Issues, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - Other MSD Candidates, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - Endorsements, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 109)
    - Literature, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 110)
    - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 111)
    - Campaign Strategy, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 112)
    - Election Statistics, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 113)
    - Township Information, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 114)
    - Questionnaires, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 115)
    - Democratic Party Events, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 116)
    - Coffee Thank Yous, c. 1970 (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Miscellaneous,, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - Miscellaneous,, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 119)
    - Events, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Sub-Series E: 1990 Campaign for County Clerk
    - Press Releases, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 121)
- Series II: Personal Papers
  - Scope and Content note: This series contains the files collected by Alter pertaining to her organizational affiliations, her tenure at the Metropolitan Sanitation District, conferences and events, and topical files on issues that she worked on. The sub series are divided into Organizations, Metropolitan Sanitation District, Events, and Topics.
  - Sub-Series A: Organizations
    - Department Report, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 122)
    - Illinois Democratic Women's Caucus, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - Illinois Democratic Women's Caucus, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - Illinois Democratic Women's Caucus, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - Miscellaneous Affiliates, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - Illinois Public Officials Lists - 1974 (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - Democratic Party, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - Illinois Environmental Council, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - Independent Precinct Organization Endorsement, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 130)
    - Independent Voters of Illinois, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 131)
    - Chicago Women's Political Caucus, 1977-1978 (Box 13, Folder 132)
    - Art Institute of Chicago Junior Museum, 1964-1968 (Box 13, Folder 133)
    - Theatre Programs, 1961-1966 (Box 13, Folder 134)
    - International Visitors, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 135)
    - Democratic Party, 1969-1971 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - Democratic National Committee - Women's Activities, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - Democratic National Convention, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 138)
    - Democratic National Convention, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 139)
    - Illinois Democratic Women's Caucus, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 140)
    - Democratic Party, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 141)
    - Democratic Party, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 142)
    - Miscellaneous Democratic Women's Groups, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - International Hospitality Center, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - Illinois Democratic Women's Caucus, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 145)
    - Democratic National Convention, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 146)
    - Democratic National Convention, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 147)
    - Art Institute - The Women's Board, 1975-1977 (Box 15, Folder 148)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 15, Folder 149)
    - Art Institute of Chicago - Women's Board minutes, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 150)
    - Art Institute of Chicago - Women's Board minutes, 1993-1996 (Box 16, Folder 151)
    - Ragdale Foundation, 1990-1993 (Box 16, Folder 152)
    - Ragdale Foundation, 1989-1991 (Box 16, Folder 153)
    - Women's Issue Network Foundation, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - Women's Issue Network Foundation, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 155)
    - Women's Issue Network Foundation, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 156)
    - Women's Issue Network Foundation, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 157)
    - Chicago Wildflower Works [clippings], 1985-1988 (Box 17, Folder 158)
    - Chicago Wildflower Works [clippings], 1985-1988 (Box 17, Folder 159)
    - Chicago Wildflower Works [clippings], 1985-1988 (Box 18, Folder 160)
    - Board of Directors Lists, 1981-1990 (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - Women's Organizations A-I, 1972-1990 (Box 18, Folder 162)
    - Women's Organizations J-Z, 1972-1990 (Box 18, Folder 163)
    - Women's Organizations - Directories, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 164)
  - Sub-Series B: Metropolitan Sanitation District
    - Metropolitan Sanitation District, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 165)
    - Tunnel and Reservoir Plan (TARP), 1978 (Box 19, Folder 166)
    - Newsletters, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Board Meeting Minutes, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 168)
    - MSD News [intermittent series], 1972-1982 (Box 19, Folder 169)
    - Metropolitan Water Reclamation District, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 170)
    - Annual Report, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 171)
    - History, 1927; 1973-1983 (Box 19, Folder 172)
    - Metropolitan Water Reclamation District, 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 173)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 174)
    - The Alter Report, 1984-1985 (Box 19, Folder 175)
    - Chicago Riverfront, 1984-1990 (Box 19, Folder 176)
    - Water Reclamation District, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 177)
    - Speeches and Press Releases, 1977-1985 (Box 20, Folder 178)
    - Speeches and Press Releases, 1975-1987 (Box 20, Folder 179)
    - Speeches and Press Releases, 1973-1979 (Box 20, Folder 180)
    - Machinist Exam Complaint, 1990-1991 (Box 20, Folder 181)
    - Annual Reports [intermittent series], 1977-1989 (Box 20, Folder 182)
    - Chicago Water, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 183)
    - "Cook County Observer" [intermittent series], 1975-1983 (Box 21, Folder 184)
    - "Cook County Observer" [intermittent series], 1984-1989 (Box 21, Folder 185)
    - Memos, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 186)
    - Memos, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 187)
    - Memos, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 188)
    - Memos, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 189)
    - Memos, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 190)
    - Memos, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 191)
    - Memos, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 192)
    - Memos, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 193)
    - Memos, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 194)
    - Memos, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 195)
    - Memos, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 196)
    - Memos, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 197)
  - Sub-Series C: Events
    - Campaign Conference for Democratic Women, 1974-1976 (Box 23, Folder 198)
    - International Women's Year Conference, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 199)
    - Governor Walker Inauguration, 1973-1976 (Box 23, Folder 200)
    - Democratic National Convention, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 201)
    - Chicago Foreign Policy Conference, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 202)
    - Michael Reese Medical Center Benefit, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 203)
    - Democratic Midterm Convention, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 204)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 205)
    - 1988 Democratic National Convention, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 206)
    - Bright New City Forum, 1990-1992 (Box 24, Folder 207)
    - "Squeaky Wheel" Broadcast Scripts, 1986-1984 (Box 24, Folder 208)
    - 1996 Democratic National Convention, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 209)
    - Miscellaneous, 1985-1988 (Box 24, Folder 210)
    - National Women's Conference, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 211)
  - Sub-Series D: Topics
    - Governor Dan Walker - State of the State address, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 212)
    - Governor Dan Walker - PR, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 213)
    - Criminal Justice, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 214)
    - Workmen's Compensation, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 215)
    - Lt. Governor Neil Hartigan, 1974-1976 (Box 25, Folder 216)
    - Honesty Initiative, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 217)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 218)
    - Labor, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 219)
    - Post-Secondary Education Master Plan, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 220)
    - Mental Health, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 221)
    - Nursing, 1973-1980 (Box 25, Folder 222)
    - Political Honesty Campaign, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 223)
    - General Clippings, 1972-1975 (Box 25, Folder 224)
    - Pesticide 2, 4, 5-T, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 225)
    - Women, 1972-1978 (Box 26, Folder 226)
    - No Earth Fertilizer, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 227)
    - Clippings - TARP, 1977-1978 (Box 26, Folder 228)
    - Stevenson Campaign, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 229)
    - Stevenson Campaign, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 230)
    - Political Honesty Initiative, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 231)
    - 6 PM Meat Sales, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 232)
    - Consumer Rights, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 233)
    - Criminal Justice, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 234)
    - Consumer Rights, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 235)
    - Ballot Order, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 236)
    - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 237)
    - General Correspondence, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 238)
    - General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 239)
    - General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 240)
    - General Correspondence, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 241)
    - General Correspondence, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 242)
    - General Correspondence, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 243)
    - General Correspondence, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 244)
    - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 245)
    - Bride of the Year, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 246)
    - Contact Lists, 1966-1971 (Box 28, Folder 247)
    - Women and Politics, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 248)
    - Adlai Stevenson III - U.S Senate Campaign, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 249)
    - United Mine Workers, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 250)
    - Women in Politics, 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 251)
    - 1977 Inaugurations, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 252)
    - Illinois Women, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 253)
    - Miscellaneous [clippings], 1977 (Box 29, Folder 254)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 29, Folder 255)
    - Campaign Publications, undated (Box 29, Folder 256)
    - Campaign Strategy, undated (Box 29, Folder 257)
    - Miscellaneous [photo], undated (Box 29, Folder 258)
    - Solid Waste, 1986-1991 (Box 29, Folder 259)
    - Ethnic Organizations, 1986-1990 (Box 29, Folder 260)
    - Solid Waste, 1981-1987 (Box 29, Folder 261)
    - Sludge Management, 1975-1978 (Box 30, Folder 262)
    - High School and College, 1942-1950 (Box 30, Folder 263)
    - Diary, undated (Box 30, Folder 264)
    - College Internship Application, 1949-1950 (Box 30, Folder 265)
    - Correspondence and Miscellaneous, 1950-1952 (Box 30, Folder 266)
    - High School Notebook, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 267)
    - Scrapbook, 1951 (Box 31, Folder 268)
    - Recordings [45 rpm album], undated (Box 31, Folder 269)
    - Health Assessment for Southeast Chicago, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 270)
    - Aging, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 271)
    - Aging, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 272)
    - College History Class Notes, circa 1950 (Box 31, Folder 273)
    - Japan Trip, 1981-1990 (Box 31, Folder 274)
    - Japan Trip, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 275)
    - Japan Trip, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 276)
    - MSD - Reports and Events, 1976-1989 (Box 32, Folder 277)
    - Correspondence and Events, 1966-1998 (Box 32, Folder 278)
    - Biographical [photo], undated (Box 32, Folder 279)
- Series III: Metropolitan Sanitary District Subject Files
  - Scope and Content Note: This series contains the subject files collected during Alter's tenure as Commissioner of the Metropolitan Sanitary District, and reflects the scope of her work during this period.
  - Affirmative Action - Women, 1978-1988 (Box 33, Folder 280)
  - Affirmative Action - Women, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 281)
  - Affirmative Action - Women Laborers, 1979-1981 (Box 33, Folder 282)
  - Affirmative Action - Women Laborers, 1979-1981 (Box 33, Folder 283)
  - Affirmative Action - Women in Non-Traditional Jobs, 1986-1990 (Box 33, Folder 284)
  - Affirmative Action - Women in Non-Traditional Jobs, 1986-1990 (Box 34, Folder 285)
  - Affirmative Action - Women, 1980-1989 (Box 34, Folder 286)
  - Affirmative Action - Women, 1980-1989 (Box 34, Folder 287)
  - Affirmative Action - Women, 1980-1989 (Box 34, Folder 288)
  - Affirmative Action - Women, 1980-1989 (Box 35, Folder 289)
  - Affirmative Action - Women, 1980-1989 (Box 35, Folder 290)
  - Affirmative Action - Women and MSD Ordinance, 1989-1990 (Box 35, Folder 291)
  - Affirmative Action - Women and MSD Ordinance, 1989-1990 (Box 35, Folder 292)
  - Affirmative Action - Women and MSD Ordinance, 1989-1990 (Box 35, Folder 293)
  - Affirmative Action - Women and MSD Ordinance, 1989-1990 (Box 36, Folder 294)
  - Affirmative Action - Women and MSD Ordinance, 1989-1990 (Box 36, Folder 295)
  - Affirmative Action, 1986-1988 (Box 36, Folder 296)
  - Affirmative Action - Apprenticeships, 1980-1989 (Box 36, Folder 297)
  - Affirmative Action - Newsclips, 1980-1989 (Box 36, Folder 298)
  - Affirmative Action - Women and 257 Reports, 1980-1989 (Box 36, Folder 299)
  - Affirmative Action - Women Newsclips, 1986-1989 (Box 37, Folder 300)
  - Affirmative Action - Robinson Group, 1978-1980 (Box 37, Folder 301)
  - Affirmative Action - Women Newsclips, 1978-1979 (Box 37, Folder 302)
  - Affirmative Action - Robinson Group, 1981-1988 (Box 37, Folder 303)
  - Articles - MSD, 1987-1989 (Box 37, Folder 304)
  - Ashley Woods, 1986-1987 (Box 37, Folder 305)
  - A - Miscellaneous, 1982-1989 (Box 37, Folder 306)
  - A - Constituent Inquiries, 1974-1982 (Box 38, Folder 307)
  - A - Constituent Inquiries, 1974-1982 (Box 38, Folder 308)
  - Bidding and Bid Rigging, 1986-1988 (Box 38, Folder 309)
  - Bidding, 1973-1990 (Box 38, Folder 310)
  - BILY, 1982-1985 (Box 39, Folder 311)
  - BILY, 1982-1985 (Box 39, Folder 312)
  - Bond Fund - Misuse, 1979-1990 (Box 39, Folder 313)
  - Budget, 1982-1989 (Box 39, Folder 314)
  - Budget, 1977-1989 (Box 40, Folder 315)
  - Budget Systems, 1973-1978 (Box 40, Folder 316)
  - B - Miscellaneous, 1977-1990 (Box 40, Folder 317)
  - B - Constituent Inquiries, 1974-1989 (Box 40, Folder 318)
  - Center for Neighborhood Technology, 1982-1990 (Box 40, Folder 319)
  - Chicago Park District, 1979-1988 (Box 41, Folder 320)
  - Civic Federation, 1974-1989 (Box 41, Folder 321)
  - Composting, 1976-1986 (Box 41, Folder 322)
  - Composting, 1976-1986 (Box 41, Folder 323)
  - Credit Union, 1978-1989 (Box 41, Folder 324)
  - C - Miscellaneous, 1985-1990 (Box 42, Folder 325)